A Guide to the Papers of John Dos Passos, 1918-2000
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John Dos Passos, 1918-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5950-cn
This collection consists of (ca.) 200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited by Lucy Dos Passos Coggin on 2000 November 22.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains a manuscript poem by Dos Passos "Beer is Free to Soldiers," 1919 February 24. There are also letters to Dawn Powell, 1937-1965; copies of postcards to Mr. and Mrs. Terry Farnsworth and Adelaide Lawson Gaylor; some Dos Passos family letters; and some miscellaneous postcards originally inserted in Memoires de Philippe de Commynes.
The collection also contains a modern copy of an 1812 baptismal certificate in Portuguese; World War I aerial photographs; a brochure for the Browne Art Class Season of 1940; a marriage certificate for John Dos Passos and Katherine Smith, 1929; "The Marriage Service" for John Dos Passos and Elizabeth Holdridge, 1949; clippings; and printed material regarding Dos Passos including programs for productions of U.S.A. reviews of U.S.A.
Finally the collection contains a copy of Days Near Rome by Augustus J. C. Hare with pressed plants between its pages.
Contents List
- Aerial Photographs [ca. World War I ?]
- "The Art of Married Life" with a marriage certificate for John Dos Passos and Katherine Smith 1929 Aug 19
- Baptismal Certificate & Other Dos Passos Family Information 1812, 1960, n.d.
- "The Browne Art Class Season of 1940" Brochure, George Elmer Browne Instructor, Provincetown-on-Cape Cod, Massachusetts 1940 Jul 1- Sep 1
- Copies of Letters from John Dos Passos to Dawn Powell (originals at Columbia University) ca. 1937-1965
- Copies of Postcards from John Dos Passos to Mr. & Mrs. Terry Farnsworth and Adelaide Lawson Gaylor ca. 1930-1969
- Correspondence of Dos Passos Family 1932, 1980-1983, n.d., 6 items
- Days Near Rome containing samples of pressed and dried plants between its pages [1907 copyright]
- Envelopes addressed to Mr. & Mrs. John Dos Passos (Empty) ca. 1942-1967, n.d.
- "The Marriage Service" for John Dos Passos and Elizabeth Holdridge 1949 Aug 6
- Memoires De Philippe De Commynes, with postcards formerly inserted between its pages 1901
- News clippings ca. 1959-1999, n.d.
- Poem, AMs, 5 p., with the first line, "Beer is Free to Soldiers" 1919 Feb 24
- Postcards 1955-1962, n.d.
- Printed Material re John Dos Passos 1972, 2000
- Programs for Productions of John Dos Passos' U.S.A.1964, n.d.
- Reviews re U.S.A.[1932], & 1939